So personal accidental insurance.  So as
you saw some time back you had
posted on your channel Top Health Insurance
Policies of 2026 with IRDA ratios and
everything.  Our video today is about Top
Personal Accidental Insurance Plans of
2026.  What is a Personal Accidental Insurance Plan
?  And how is it different
from your health insurance policy.  So a
health insurance policy is an indemnity
policy.  Meaning, if there is any
hospitalization, then whatever your bill is,
it will be paid by a health insurance company.
Personal Accidental Policy is a
fixed benefit policy.  Where there is an
accidental injury or accidental
death, the disability along with the injury, whether
temporary, partial or permanent, will be
covered.  And if death occurs, the
death benefit will be given in your personal
accidental insurance policy.  So where
your health insurance policy is not useful
, personal accidental insurance
policy comes in handy.  Many detailed
videos on personal accidental insurance are available on our channel.
We have also included a real life case study.  Where
he received a claim of Rs 8 lakh from a
personal accidental policy due to injury.
So I have also put the video link below.   You
will definitely see that.  Personal accidental
policy is generally cheaper as compared
to your health insurance policy and its
premium remains the same from 18 to 65
years of age.  So the same premium has to be paid.  It is
not different
like health insurance.  So let's talk about
which personal accidental insurance
policies you can consider.  A
disclaimer before starting the video
please do your due diligence regarding these companies and
their policies before taking any
decision.
[Music]
Quick reminder before we start the video,
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, do so so that
you get the
right information at the right time.  Today we will compare
five personal accidental insurance
plans.  Which ones are they?  Neevapa
Personal Accidental Plan, HDFC and Gokoti
Suraksha Plan, Aditya Birla Active
Secure Plan, Tata AIG Accident Guard
Plus and ICIC LB Family Sheet.  So first of all we will
look at the ICR of these companies.
ICR stands for Incurred Claim Ratio.  Meaning
how much money came to the insurance company
and how much money they paid in claims,
this is called Incurred Claim Ratio.  Niwapa has
61.22% This is the latest 232
IRD Annual Report on S.  HDFC has 84.85%,
Aditya Birla has 71.5%,
Tata AIG has 76.24 and ICICI has
82.24. Let us discuss here
what is the eligibility criteria
of these policies?  The entry age for Neevapa Personal
Accidental Plan is 18 years.
You can enter this policy for a maximum of 65 years.
But you
can continue it for lifetime.  HDFC Ergo
coverage is also available for those aged 18 to 65 years.
Aditya Birla Active Secure Plan can be
taken from 5 years to 65 years.  Tata
EIG 18 Years to 70 Years & ICICI LBA
Family Shield 3 Months to 65 Years.  This
plan can be taken as a family floater or individual
depending on the terms and conditions of each policy.
So, it is found in families as well as
in individuals.
If we talk about eligibility, then for how many times you are
eligible to take the policy.  Because
this is an income based plan based on how much
income you have.  On that basis the company tells you
that you can take insurance up to that amount.
So your income proof goes.
Your eligibility is checked on that basis.
So the eligibility criteria of NIVAPA is that if
you are salaried then you can get cover up to 20 times of your annual
income.  If you
are self-employed, you can get cover up to 25 times your annual income.
If you have unearned
income, it means only interest income,
pension income, all these are income which is called passive income, then
15 times of annual
income.  If you are non-earning then
you will get a maximum policy of Rs 50 lakh.
10 Times of Annual Income in HDFC Ago Only for
Earning Person.  12
Times of Annual Income Only for Earning
Person in Aditya Birla.  If salaried in Tata AIG then 10
times of annual income and if self employed then
20 times of annual income.  In ICIC LBA
Family Shield, if you are salaried then 10 times
and if you are self-employed then 20 times of
annual income.  Your ITR of three years is
seen.  Its average is calculated.
You get this policy in its multiplier benefit.
So if you already have any personal
accidental policy, then
you will also include that in the total.  Like
in term insurance.
Financial eligibility also has to be checked in term insurance.
Here also, you will
take the policy only after checking the financial eligibility.  Sum Assured Options
that are available.  There are options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs
10 crore in Neevapa.  Options ranging from Rs
10 lakh to Rs 2 crore in HDFCO quota security.
5 lakh to 20 crore in Aditya Birla Active Secure.  Policy tenure options available are Rs 5
lakh to Rs 5 crore in Tata AIG Accident Guard Plus, Rs
5 lakh to Rs 1 crore in ICICI LBA Family Shield.
One year, two year and three year
policies are available in all the five plans, which we call multi tenure
policies.  You
can pay premium for two or three years together so that the
company gives you some discounts.   The
policy type we were talking about,
both individual and family floater
are available in Neevapa.
Individual policy is available in HDFC Koti Suraksha.  This means that if
husband and wife want to buy it, they will have to
buy two individual plans.
You can also take a family floater in Niva.
Both individual and family floater are available in Aditya Birla also.  Individual Family Floater in Tata AIG
Individual plan is only available in ICICI.
Emergency Accidental Hospitalization.  Neeva has
inbuilt BPA.  If there is
any hospitalization due to an accident, then that
is also covered in this plan.  So accidental emergency hospitalization is covered up to 10% of sum
assured maximum up to Rs 5 lakh.
It is up to ₹1 lakh in HDFC Ergo.
Optional in Aditya Birla is 1% of sum
assured.  Maximum ₹1 lakh.  Tata EIG offers
10% off sum assured, maximum up to Rs 5 lakh. ICICI Lo
LBA offers minimum Rs 5000 and maximum
up to Rs 2 lakh.  So if there is any
accidental emergency and
hospitalization is required, one option is to
use your health insurance policy.
Secondly, you
can also use your personal accidental policy.  So that the
no claim bonus and all that of your health insurance policy does not go
waste.  Then let's talk about
accidental death, the
main purpose of these plants is to
cover your accidental death.  Every company will give you 100% of the
sum assured, whether
it is Rs 25 lakh, Rs 50 lakh or Rs 1 crore, to the
beneficiary or nominee on
accidental death.  Then comes the emergency road
ambulance that if
we need an emergency road ambulance to go to the hospital
then it is covered up to ₹25,000 in Nivamuppa.
HDFC Kothi Suraksha up to ₹1 lakh,
Aditya Birla Active Secure Plan up
to ₹10,000, Tata AIG Accident Guard
Plus up to ₹25,000 and ICIC Lombard
Family Shield Permanent Total
Disability, that is, if the insured
travels with Permanent Total Disability within 365
days of accident, then the company will pay the claim.   The
table of how much and how it will give is in front of you.
This is a complete and irreversible
loss.  So he becomes permanently disabled.
So if any two limbs get damaged,
sight of both eyes, speech and hearing of
both eyes due to accident, this is it.  Yes.
Combination of One Limb and Sight of One Eye:
In this combination, 100% of sum assured will be given.  The
entire sum assured will be given to you.  Now if there is complete and
irrecoverable loss of one limb, sight of one eye is lost
then 50% will be given.  So
according to this table, you get permanent
total disability.  If there is permanent partial
disability, meaning it is permanent
but partial of any body part, then
also the insurance company gives some percentage, what is that,
let us see through the table, if
each arm at the shoulder joint is lost, there is
loss of one arm, then 70% will be given, if each arm is lost
to a point above the elbow joint, then 65% will be given,
these are very specific things.
If each thumb is cut, you will get 20%.  If one
index finger is damaged, you will get 10%.
Ah, if one toe gets damaged, you will get 2%.   If
hearing gets impaired, you will get 30%.  Sense
of smell, sense of taste.  So, this
is all in permanent partial disability.
Meaning there is irrecoverable loss, but it is a partial
loss, not a total loss.  So, accordingly
you will get sum assured as percentage of
death sum assured.  After this comes temporary
total disability.  So, this is the benefit due to which
this policy should actually be taken.
Temporary total disability means
if the person is temporarily disabled.   It
is disabled for some time.  For example, a
fracture occurred.  For example, if you get injured, fall
and undergo a surgery and the doctor
advises you on bed rest and you are unable to go to work or
perform your duties, then
you get Temporary Total Disability Benefit which is
percentage of sum assured. So, it is
different for every company. For example,
in Nivapa, there is an option of TT which is Temporary Total
Disability Plus and then there is TTD Lite.
You can choose from these two which one you
want to choose. TTD Plus gives you
2% of sum assured per week, maximum Rs. 75,000
per week for a period of up to 52 weeks.
TTD Lite gives 1% of sum assured per
week, maximum Rs. 50,000 per week and up to 104
weeks. In HDFC Ergo Koti Suraksha, you get 1% of
sum assured maximum Rs. 1 lakh per
week for 104 weeks. In Aditya Birla Active
Secure, you get weekly benefit Rs.
1000-2000.  3000 4000 and goes up to 50000 and the
maximum TT can be up to two
times of income up to 100 weeks which can be only
twice of your income
and up to 100 weeks so the
TT in NEVAPA that is optional you will have to add it.
HDFC Ergo has it inbuilt
in the policy.  It is also inbuilt in Aditya Birla.
If you are taking a protect policy in Tata AIG,
Tata AIG Accident
Guard Plus Protect is optional.  If you take Alt
or Premier then it
is inbuilt.  1% of Accidental Death Sum Assured and
Rs.50000 for a maximum of 104 weeks.
Weekly benefit is available in ICICI Family Shield.
10000 15000 20000 per week for 104
weeks.  This is an optional benefit.  You
can select.  Loan Protector.  So Loan
Protector is an add on which is available
where your loan is also protected.
Meaning you have some outstanding loan running.
So if you take this add-on,
what happens is that on death, the
outstanding loan amount for which
you have taken cover is also given.  Suppose
you have a loan of Rs 50 lakh and you are
taking a personal accidental policy of Rs 50 lakh.
Along with that, loan protector add on is also being taken.
So, on death, you will
get a personal accidental claim of Rs 50.  Along with this,
sum assured of loan protector will also be available.
Latest Principal Outstanding Balance on Which Is S.  At the
time of death, the
insurance company will pay the principal outstanding.  The bank
will provide that on death.  So she will do it on the company.
So this rider is available in NEEPA in
which latest principal outstanding
loan amount as per bank details maximum
up to base sum assured.  So, he cannot exceed Rs 50 lakhs, it will
remain below that.  Not available in HDFC Ago.
Aitya B is available in Birla at Rs 1 lakh to Rs 1
crore.  Three EMIs up to Rs 50,000.
You can take a loan protector from Rs 1 lakh to Rs 1 crore.
Three EMIs are paid by you.  You have to choose these options from up
to Rs 50,000, Rs 75,000, Rs 1 lakh to Rs 5 lakh.
Up to 25% off
sum assured and actual whichever is
lower in Tata EIG Accident Guard Plus.  Adventure sports.  So adventure
sports is also an add on that an
accident happened while doing adventure sports.  So
generally your policies do not cover it
because you knew that you meant it was
self-inflicting.  You know that they
even make you sign that if anything happens then they will not be
responsible.  Similarly,
insurance companies are also not
responsible.  So you can take the add on of adventure sports.
Available in Nivapa.
100% of Base Sum Assured and Permanent Total
Disability Sum Assured.  Not available in HDFC.
Your Aditya Birla Benefit
Equal to Accident Plan will be paid
in Adventure Sports.  Maximum up to 10
lax.  ICIC is also available in LBA Family Shield.
Then let's talk about compassionate
visits in the case of adventure sports.  So
some percentage is covered
on compassionate grounds, that is also mentioned.
Transportation of Motley Remains.  If the motel
remains have to be transported
from one place to another, that is also covered.
Up to 1% of base sum up to a maximum of ₹1
lakh in Neevapa.  Not available in HDFCO.
Aitya Birla offers a lump sum benefit of
₹50,000.  Tata AIG offers 1% of
base sum assured up to a maximum of ₹25,000 combined with
funeral expenses and last rite
benefits in your ICICI LB Family
Shield plan.  Air Ambulance Niwapa has
20% of Accidental Death Summed up to a maximum of 5
Lacs for Air Ambulance.
Air ambulance is not available in HDFC Bank.  It is
not covered even in Birla.  Tata AIG has up to 5
lax.  Air ambulance is also covered under the ICIC LBA Family Shield.
Hospital Daily Cash
means that if there is any accidental hospitalization,
then daily cash benefit will also be available.
These are basically all the variants in Neeva BPA.  There are
some add ons.  You
can design the policy as per your requirement.  So
Hospital Daily Cash which is 2525% of base sum
assured maximum Rs 5000 for maximum 30 days.
HDFC ARGO has ₹3000 per day.
Not available in Aditya Birla.  Tata IG offers
5% of Accidental Death Sum Assured up to Rs 5000
whichever is less for a maximum of 60 days and
is also available in ICICI Family Shield.
Elderly Care to take care of your parents after accidental
death.  So 10% of
base sum assured maximum IAR ₹5 lakh.  And
in HDFC Ergo the maximum amount available is Rs 5 lakh.
5% of base sum assured is not available in other companies.
Education of Dependent
Children 10% of Base Sum Assured Maximum
₹5 Lakh.  10% of base sum assured up to a
maximum of ₹1 lakh in HDFC Ergo.
10% of base sum assured maximum Rs 10 lakh at Aditya Birla.   It
is optional in Tata AIG that if the child's age reaches
30 years then a fixed sum will be given.  10% of
sum assured and Rs 1 lakh whichever is less.
Benefits up to Rs 10 lakh are available under ICICI Lombard Family Shield.  Then comes
marriage expenses for children.
Money for children's marriage will be available in Niva Bhupa at
20% of base sum assured.  Maximum
₹1 lakh.  The benefit is not available in HDFC Ago, Aitya, Tata
and ICICI.
Broken Bonus Benefit.  Basically, if a
bone breaks, a percentage
of your sum assured is given.  There is also
percentage of sum assured in Nivapa.  Depending on
which bone is broken, the
maximum amount you will get is ₹1 lakh.  And
in HDFC Ago, maximum benefit is ₹1 lakh,
in Aditya Birla you can choose benefit up to ₹1 lakh, 3 lakh, 5
lakh, in Tata AIG, maximum
accidental death sum assured is given up to ₹1
lakh.  Percentage of Accidental
Death Sum Assured up to ₹1 lakh is given
in ICICI LBA Family Shield. This is designed as per the sum assured.
Prosthetics and wheelchairs are some of the
benefits that are provided in case
of accidental injuries.
Neevapa covers up to ₹1 lakh.  HDFC
Ergo is not covered in Aditya Birla.
Wheelchairs are provided at Tata AIG.  10%
off accidental death penalty up to a maximum of ₹1 lakh.
Artificial limes are given.  are covered.
10% of Accidental Day Sum Assured or
maximum ₹1 lakh.  There is
no such provision in the ICIC LB Family Shield.  Talking about comatose,
if someone goes into coma, will he
get any benefit?  Due to
accident, 25% of base M/s
Assured up to a maximum of ₹1 lakh will be given under NIVAPA.
50% off base EMI assured maximum 25 lacs at HDFC Argo.
Maximum up to
₹1 lakh in Aditya Birla, 10% of base sum
assured maximum up to ₹5 lakh in Tata IG and
it is also covered in ICICI Low LBAT Family Shield.
The percentage is decided according to the sum assured.
Talking about burns, where an
accident occurs due to burns,
there also a fixed benefit for burns
is available.  So Burns has up to base sum
assured.  Maximum you will get is Rs 550.
Get up to Rs 75,000 in HDFC Bank account in New Delhi.  This benefit is not available in Aditya Birla and Tata
and
summation up to 2.5 lakhs in ICICI.  So, these plans
are personal accidental plans, in which many
things are inbuilt and you have to
take many add-ons.  So there is a base cover and there are
add ons on top of that.  So, as per your need, you can
pick and choose whatever you feel you need
and design
your personal accidental policy for your family.
So my suggestion is that you should have a
good personal accidental policy and
if you want to cover things
that your health insurance policy will not
cover, neither will a term insurance
policy.  These are the things your
personal accidental policy will cover which is
disability.  So for that thing it is
necessary to have an accidental insurance policy.
Now let's talk about premiums.  This
is the premium for all five policies on your screen.
You can see that
I have calculated this with the base and basic riders.
You can calculate
which riders you
want to add as per your requirement
and after doing your dues, you can get a good
personal accidental insurance for yourself.
If you found this video useful,
please share it with your friends and family.
You may want to reach out to us
to buy a personal accidental policy.
Our contact number, email ID, WhatsApp
number, Google form are given below.
Contact us and we will be able to
assist you.  And before we go, a quick
reminder, if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, please do so.
So that you
get the right infection at the right time.  See you
in the next video.  Till then stay safe.
Take care.